Sylvia Beach Papers, 1887-1966 (bulk 1920s-1950s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 7: Photographs, 1881-1969; 14.1 linear feet 20 boxes
  - Subseries 7F: Photographs of Notable People, 1881-1968 June 11; 10.0 boxes (1 partial)
    - Craig, Gordon, 1940-1941 December 17; 1.0 folder
      - Clipping: Portrait of Gordon Craig Seated With Hat and Cane, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (5.25 x 3.75 inches) (Folder 25)
      - Inscribed Photograph: Gordon Craig Examining a Mask, 1941 December 17; 3; portion of 1 folder (8.25 x 8.25 inches) (Folder 25)
        Inscribed "To Sylvia from E.G.C., December 17, 1941" Includes "d'oray" in same hand.
      - Photograph: Gordon Craig Seated, Writing at a Desk, undated; 4; portion of 1 folder (7.25 x 5 inches) (Folder 25)
        Written on reverse "EGC, photo by David"
      - Inscribed Photograph: Portrait of Craig’s Daughter, 1941 February 2; 5; portion of 1 folder (2 x 1.75 inches, mounted on card 3.75 x 2.75 inches) (Folder 25)
        Inscribed "2.2.1941. For Sylvia." and "Photo taken June 1940" (on mounting behind photo), written on reverse "Sylvia Beach, 12 rue de l’Odéon, Paris VI"
    - Crosby, Harry and Caresse, 1929; 1.0 folder
      - Mounted Photographs: Caresse Crosby Standing in Front of Rock Wall (Top), And Harry Crosby Standing in Front of Plane (Bottom), circa 1929; 1; 2 copies portion of 1 folder (both 2.75 x 1.75 inches, mounted on card 7 x 2.5 inches) (Folder 26)
        Mounted one above the other with names written on rectos. Manuscript inscription to Sylvia Beach written in pencil on back of Harry Caresse print, which cannot be fully read owed to the method of mounting.
      - Oversized Photographs: Larger Copy Prints of Mounted Photographs, undated; 1.1; portion of 1 folder (both 9 x 5.5 inches, mounted on card 10.5 x 13.5 inches) (Folder 3)
        mounted side by side, no captions
    - Cummings, E. E., undated; 1; 1.0 folder (7.25 x 5 inches, mounted on card 8.25 x 6 inches) (Folder 27)
      One photograph: portrait with beret, titled "E. E. CUMMINGS" mounted on card.
    - Cunard, Nancy, undated; 1.0 folder
      - Oversized Signed Photograph: Portrait of Nancy Cunard in Profile With Cigarette by Curtis Moffat, undated; 1; Moffat, Curtis; portion of 1 folder (11.75 x 9.5 inches) (Folder 2)
        Vintage print signed "Nancy Cunard," stamped on reverse "Shakespeare and Company, Sylvia Beach, Library, Paris."
      - Photographic Postcard: Drawn Portrait by Ortiz De Zarate, Titled "Nancy Cunard," Signed by Nancy Cundard, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (5.5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 28)
    - Dillon, George, undated; 1.0 folder
      - Reproduction Photograph: Portrait of George Dillon by James Hargis Connelly From Publication, undated; 1; 1 item (6 x 5 inches) (Folder 29)
        Reproduced from Authors Today and Yesterday: A Companion Volume to Living Authors.
      - Reproduction Negative: Portrait of George Dillon by James Hargis Connelly From Publication, undated; 1 item (Folder 29)
    - Doolittle, Hilda (H.D.), 1917; 1.0 folder
      - Photograph: Formal Vingette Portrait of Hilda Doolittle, 1917; 1; 1 original and 2 copy prints portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 2.25 inches) (Folder 30)
        "H.D. 1917" written on print.
      - Reproduction Photograph: Hilda Doolittle Seated Leaning on Hand, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (8.5 x 8.5 inches) (Folder 30)
        Reproduced from a publication.
      - Reproduction Negative: Hilda Doolittle Seated Leaning on Hand, undated; 1 item (Folder 30)
      - Inscribed Formal portrait: Hilda Doolittle Signed by Man Ray, undated; 11; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 vintage print and 1 later copy print portion of 1 folder (9 x 6.75 inches (mounted on board 12 x 9 in frame 14 x 11)) (Folder 12-13)
        Signed on print: "Man Ray Paris." Inscribed on board: "To Sylvia Beach ‘ "H. D." ’"
    - Dos Passos, John, 1924; 1; Ordiorne, William; portion of 1 folder (9 x 7.5 inches) (Folder 31)
      One vintage print: Formal portrait, by William "Cicero" Odiorne of New Orleans" signed "John Dos Passos, Paris, September 1924" with "Ordiorne - New Orleans" written in ink on recto. Includes two copy prints.
    - Douglas, Norman, 1938 June 18; 1.0 folder
      - Inscribed Photograph: Norman Douglas Standing Portrait Outside, 1938 June 18; 1; portion of 1 folder (5.75 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 32)
        Inscribed "For Sylvia from Uncle Norman," inscribed on reverse "For Sylvia from Uncle Norman, 18 June 1938"
      - Photograph of a Painting: Norman Douglas Portrait by Desmond Harmsworth, undated; 2; Vaux, Marc, 1895-1971; 2 copies portion of 1 folder (8.5 x 6.75 inches, mounted on card 10 x 8.25 inches) (Folder 32)
        "N.D. 1933 Desmond," written on artwork. Photograph by Marc Vaux, rue de Vaugirard, Paris.
    - Eastman, Max, 1922; 1; 1.0 folder (9.25 x 7.25 inches) (Folder 1)
      One photograph: inscribed "To Sylvia Beach from Max Eastman, 1922"
    - Eisenstein, Serge, 1930; 1; Binder, Alexander; 1.0 folder (9.25 x 6.75 inches) (Folder 2)
      One photograph: inscribed "To my dear friend Silvya Beach, Cordially, Serge Eisenstein, Paris 21/III ’30," dated on reverse "Eisenstein 1930," stamped on reverse "Atelier Binder, Berlin" and "Copyright by A. Binder, Berlin"
    - Eliot, T.S., 1936 May-1964 June; 1.0 folder
      - Snapshot: T.S. Eliot Reading at Shakespeare and Company by Gisèle Freund, 1936 May; Freund, Gisèle; 1 vintage print (5.5 x 7 inches) (Folder 3)
        Written on reverse "Photo Gisèle, 7 rue de l’Odéon, Paris-VI"
      - Portrait: T.S. Eliot Seated With Virginia Woolf by Jean De Menasce, circa 1964 June; 1; Menasce, Jean de; 1 vintage print and 2 copy prints portion of 1 folder (6.25 x 4.5 inches) (Folder 3)
        Stamped on reverse "Shakespeare and Company, Sylvia Beach, Library, Paris," attached note: "T.S. Eliot with Virginia Woolf, drinking tea in Bloomsbury, early 20s, by Jean de Menasce, given by him to Sylvia Beach." Additional information provided by a letter dated 1997 (removed to collection file) states the location as the Green Room at Garsington from a photograph of that room on page 49 of Heilbrun's Lady Ottoline's Album, and the date as most probably June 1924 ( The Letters of Virginia Woolf, III 116 n. 3).
      - Clipping: Portrait of T.S. Eliot, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (4.75 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 3)
      - Clipping: T.S. Eliot With Second Wife, Valérie Fletcher, From Le Figaro Littéraire, 1958 January 4; 3; portion of 1 folder (7.75 x 4.5 inches) (Folder 3)
      - Group Photograph: T.S. Eliot at the Faber Reception for W.H. Auden in Russell Square, With Louis MacNeice, Auden, Ted Hughes, And Stephen Spender, By Mark Gerson, circa 1960; 4; Gerson, Mark, 1921-; portion of 1 folder (6.75 x 8.25 inches) (Folder 3)
        Typescript note attached to back of print. Stamped on reverse "Photograph by Mark Gerson"
      - Portraits: T.S. Eliot by Man Ray, undated; portions of 2 boxes
        - Formal Portrait: T.S. Eliot Looking Straight Ahead by Man Ray, undated; 12; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 vintage print and 1 copy print portion of 1 folder (9 x 7 inches (mounted in frame 14.5 x 11.5)) (Folder 14-15)
        - Copy prints: T.S. Eliot Looking Straight Ahead by Man Ray, undated; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 2 copy prints (Folder 3)
        - Formal Portrait: T.S. Eliot Looking Right by Man Ray, undated; 13; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 vintage print and 1 copy print portion of 1 folder (9 x 7.25 inches (mounted in frame 14.5 x 11.5)) (Folder 16-17)
        - Formal portrait: T.S. Eliot Looking Down and Left by Man Ray, undated; 14; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 vintage print portion of 1 folder (6.25 x 4 inches (mounted in frame 14.5 x 11.5)) (Folder 18)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1923 September-1924; 1.0 folder
      - Photographic Postcard: Drawing of Havelock Ellis by Paul-Émile Bécat, 1924; 1; portion of 1 folder (5.5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 4)
      - Inscribed Portrait: Havelock Ellis by John Trevor of Hampstead, 1923 September; 2; Trevor, John; portion of 1 folder (6 x 4.25 inches, mounted on card 10.25 x 8.25 inches) (Folder 4)
        Inscribed "To Sylvia Beach with best regards from Havelock Ellis—Sept. 1923" on recto. Photographer's signature on verso.
      - Signed Portrait: Havelock Ellis by John Trevor of Hampstead, 1923 September; 3; Trevor, John; portion of 1 folder (6 x 4.25 inches, mounted on card 10.25 x 8 inches) (Folder 4)
        Signed "Havelock Ellis, Sept. 1923."
      - Insribed portrait: Havelock Ellis by John Trevor of Hampstead, undated; 4; Trevor, John; portion of 1 folder (5.75 x 4 inches, mounted on card 10.25 x 8.25 inches) (Folder 4)
        Inscribed "With kind regards from Havelock Ellis"
    - Fargue, Léon-Paul, 1921; 1.0 folder
      - Snapshot: Léon-Paul Fargue With a Beard, circa 1921; 1; portion of 1 folder (2.75 x 4 inches) (Folder 5)
        Included note and envelope state the photograph was loaned to Agathe Valéry 9 April 1962 and returned two days later. Typescript note reads: "Petite photographie de LEON-PAUL FARGUE que Farque a donnée à Sylvia Beach en 1921 (une des rares photos de lui avec sa barbe).
      - Photographic postcard: Léon-Paul Fargue Seated at a Table With the Prince of Bassiano (Roffredo Caetani), An Unidentified Woman, The Princess of Bassiano (Marguerite Caetani), And Mlle. Curonio, undated; 2; 2 copies portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 5.5 inches) (Folder 5)
        Stamped on reverse of one copy: "Shakespeare and Company, Sylvia Beach, Library, Paris." Written on the back of second copy: "Pc. di Bassiano, L.P. Fargue, Cp-X, Pss. di Bassiano, Mlle. Curonio," no stamp.
      - News Photograph: Léon-Paul Fargue at His Glass Factory With Sylvia Beach for the New York Times, undated; Wide World Photos, Inc..; 2 vintage prints and 6 copy prints of various sizes (Folder 5)
        One print stamped "Wide World Photos" and "Photograph copyright in the United States by The New York Times."
      - Snapshot: Léon-Paul Fargue With Marie Monnier, circa 1921; 1 item (Folder 5)
    - Faulkner, William, undated; 1.0 folder
      - Reproduction Photograph: Formal Portrait From Publication, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (7 x 5 inches, mounted on card 7.75 x 5.5 inches) (Folder 6)
      - Reproduction Negative: Formal Portrait From Publication, undated; 1 item (Folder 6)
      - Reproduction Photograph: Standing in Front of a Small Plane, undated; 2; 2 copies portion of 1 folder (4 x 5 inches) (Folder 6)
      - Reproduction Negative: Standing in Front of a Small Plane, undated; 1 item (Folder 6)
      - Reproduction Photograph: Seated Outside, Wearing a Hat and Smoking a Pipe, undated; 3; portion of 1 folder (4.6 x 3.5 inches, mounted on card 6.25 x 4.5 inches) (Folder 6)
      - Photograph: Portrait in Profile, Lighting a Pipe, undated; 4; 2 copies portion of 1 folder (9.5 x 7 inches) (Folder 6)
      - Photograph: Seated on a Couch, Smoking a Pipe, undated; 5; portion of 1 folder (7 x 9.5 inches) (Folder 6)
    - Figari, Pedro, 1926 April 26; 1; 1.0 folder (11.75 x 9 inches, on card) (Folder 7)
      One photograph: inscribed "À Sylvia Beach: amitié, sympathie, et fie, Paris, le 26 avril 1926 Pedro Figari"
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 1928; 1.0 folder
      - Snapshot: F. Scott Fitzgerald Sitting and Looking at Camera With Adrienne Monnier in Front of Shakespeare and Company, 1928; 1; Beach, Sylvia; 1 vintage print and 2 later prints portion of 1 folder (4.25 x 2.75 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Negative: F. Scott Fitzgerald Sitting and Looking at Camera With Adrienne Monnier in Front of Shakespeare and Company, 1928; Beach, Sylvia; 1 original negative (Folder 8)
      - Snapshot: F. Scott Fitzgerald Sitting and Looking Up With Adrienne Monnier in Front of Shakespeare and Company, 1928; 2; Beach, Sylvia; 4 copies and 1 photographic reproduction from a publication portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 3 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Negative: F. Scott Fitzgerald Sitting and Looking Up With Adrienne Monnier in Front of Shakespeare and Company, 1928; 1 orginal negative and 1 copy negative (Folder 8)
      - Snapshot: F. Scott Fitzgerald Sitting and Looking at Adrienne Monnier in Front of Shakespeare and Company, 1928; 1 vintage print (Folder 8)
      - Negative: F. Scott Fitzgerald Sitting and Looking at Adrienne Monnier in Front of Shakespeare and Company, 1928; 1 original negative (Folder 8)
      - Snapshot: F. Scott Fitzgerald Standing in Front of Shakespeare and Company With Adrienne Monnier, 1928; 3; 1 vintage print and 1 later print (4.75 x 2.75 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Reproduction Negative: F. Scott Fitzgerald's Cartoon Drawing of Party at Adrienne Monnier’S, 1928 July; 1 copy negative (Folder 8)
        Inscription in image (not on negative) reads "Paris July 1928, 18 rue de l’Odéon, Festival of St. James" from inside Sylvia Beach's copy of The Great Gatsby.
      - Portrait: F. Scott Fitzgerald Standing by Carl Van Vechten, undated; 1; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964.; 3 copies of 1 image portion of 1 folder (4.25 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 8)
        Two images have hand-written notations listing Van Vechten as photographer, one image says USIS Archives, Collection: Man Ray.
      - Clipping: Portrait of F. Scott Fitzgerald by Fareckson, undated; 1 item (Folder 8)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1927-1944; 1.0 folder
      - Portrait: Janet Flanner With Masks and Top Hat by Berenice Abbott, 1927; 1; Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991; 1 item (10 x 8 inches) (Folder 8)
        Written on reverse "Janet Flanner (Genêt) by Berenice Abbott dressed in costume for masked ball, copyright by Berenice Abbott," attached note on reverse "Janet Flanner (‘Genêt’ du ‘New Yorker’) par Berénice Abbott." Possibly a copy print.
      - Portrait: Janet Flanner With Masks and Top Hat by Berenice Abbott, 1927; 1; portion of 1 folder (10 x 7.5 inches) (Folder 9)
        Likely a copy print.
      - Clipping: Janet Flanner Standing With Sylvia Beach and Ernest Hemingway, 1944; 2; portion of 1 folder (4 x 3 inches) (Folder 9)
        Caption: "Back in Paris, Hemingway chats with Sylvia Beach, bookshop owner and James Joyce’s publisher, and Writer Janet Flanner, friends of Left Bank days"
    - Flecker, James Elroy, undated; 1.0 folder
      - Photogravure: Formal Portrait, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 3 inches) (Folder 10)
      - Photograph: Portrait in a Study, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (5.75 x 4 inches, on card 10 x 7.25 inches) (Folder 10)
        Written on recto: "James Elroy Flecker, given to Sylvia Beach by Hellé Flecker 1919"
    - Ford, Charles Henri, undated; Studio Piaz.; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      Formal portrait.
    - Forster, E.M., undated; 1; Photo Girix.; portion of 1 folder (6.5 x 4.5 inches) (Folder 12)
      One vintage print and one copy print of the same image. Written on reverse of vintage print: "E.M. Forster, photographed at the Congrès des Écrivains," stamped on reverse "Copyright Photo Girix, Paris XV, 19 rue Lakanal"
    - Gershwin, George, 1928 June; 1; Studio G. L. Manuel frères (Paris, France).; 1.0 folder (11.5 x 8.25 inches) (Folder 13)
      One photograph inscribed "For Miss Sylvia Beach, Sincerely, George Gershwin—June 1928" by G. L. Manuel frères, 47 Rue Dumont
    - Gide, André, 1919-1926; 1.0 folder
      - Group Photograph: André Gide Reading to a Crowd in Pontigny, France, 1923; 1; portion of 1 folder (4.25 x 2.5 inches, mounted on card 4.25 x 4 inches) (Folder 14)
        Group photograph. Left to right: Jean Schlumberger, Lytton Strachey, Maria van Rysselberghe, Aline Mayrisch, Boris de Schloezer(unconfirmed), Gide, André Maurois, Franz Funck-Brentano, Johan Tielrooy, Roger Martin du Gard, Jacques Heurgon,, Albert-Marie Schmidt.
        In front and below: Pierre Viénot, Marc Schlumberger, Jacques de Lacretelle and Pierre Lancel.
        Various hand-written notes on recto and verso of photograph identifying (sometimes incorrectly) various persons in the photograph. One note reads: "Photo donné à SB par Heurgon - Pontigny"
      - Inscribed Portrait: André Gide Outside Wearing Fur Stole, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (9 x 6 inches, on card) (Folder 14)
        Inscribed "à Sylvia Beach en amical souvenir, André Gide"
      - Snapshot: André Gide Reclining Outside in a Chair With Handwritten Caption, undated; 3; portion of 1 folder (1.75 x 2.25 inches) (Folder 14)
      - Photograph of a drawing: André Gide by Paul-Émile Bécat, 1919; 4; 1 large print and 1 photographic postcard portion of 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Inscribed Snapshot: André Gide on Boat in Lake Chad by Marc Allégret, 1925-1926; 1; Allégret, Marc, 1900-1973; 1 inscribed print and 1 copy print portion of 1 folder (6.5 x 8.5 inches) (Folder 14)
        Inscribed "Souvenir du Congo—1925-26, André Gide" Later copy print inscribed on reverse "André Gide on lake Tchad, Africa 1926, by Mark Allegret. By kind permission of Mark Allegret"
      - Portrait: André Gide Leaning on Hand by Gisèle Freund, undated; 1; Freund, Gisèle; 1 item (5.5 x 4 inches) (Folder 14)
    - Gilbert, Stuart, 1931; 1.0 folder
      - Mounted Photograph: At His Appartment on The Île-Saint-Louis With James and Nora Joyce, undated; 1; 1.0 folder (2.25 x 3.5 inches mounted on card 6.5 x 9.75 inches) (Folder 15)
        Mounted on board with another photograph with typescript caption from a publication.
      - Mounted Photograph: In Zurich With James Joyce and Moune Gilbert, 1931; 1 item (4.25 x 3.25 inches mounted on card 6.5 x 9.75 inches) (Folder 15)
      - Portrait: Stuart Gilbert on His Balcony on the Ile Saint-Louis for the New York Times, undated; 1; New York Times Photos.; 1.0 folder (4.5 x 7 inches) (Folder 15)
        Stamped on reverse "New York Times Photos"
    - Gillet, Louis, undated; 1.0 folder
      - Photograph: Formal Portrait Next to Mirror, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (6 x 4.25 inches) (Folder 16)
      - Inscribed Photograph: Seated Portrait With Grand-Daughter Riquette, undated; 2; Kardos, Rose; portion of 1 folder (9 x 6.5 inches, with card 13 x 9.5 inches) (Folder 16)
        Inscribed "à Miss Sylvia Beach, amie de Shakespeare et de Joyce— Le grand-père de Riquette—Louis Gillet"
    - Giono, Jean, undated; 1; Freund, Gisèle; 1.0 folder (9 x 6.5 inches) (Folder 17)
      One photograph: seated outside with two young children, stamped on reverse "Copyright Gisèle Freund, 18 rue de l’Odéon, Paris"
    - Gómez De La Serna, Ramón, circa 1931; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      Formal portrait inscribed on recto "Para Silvia rendidamenta RAMÓN"
    - Guiraldès, Ricardo, 1958 January 27; 1.0 folder
      - Photographic Postcard: Standing Outside With Wife Adelina, undated; 1; 1.0 folder (3.5 x 4.75 inches) (Folder 19)
        Inscribed on back "Pour notre chère petite Adrienne avec toute notre [?] peu dressé—Adelina & Ricardo"
      - Clipping: Notes the Commemoration of a Plaque Remembering Ricardo Guiraldès, From Figaro, 1958 January 27; 1 item (2.5 x 2.5 inches) (Folder 19)
        "Joyce y a habité" written in margin.
    - Harris, Frank, 1925; 1.0 folder
      - Photograph: View of Harris’s Room, With Accompanying Note, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (4.25 x 6.25 inches) (Folder 20)
        "Frank Harris room Cimiez Nice, gift of Annette Krim to Sylvia Beach, August 1960"
      - Inscribed Collotype: Portrait, 1925; 2; portion of 1 folder (9 x 6.75 inches) (Folder 20)
        Inscribed "Frank Harris, in all sympathy, Paris 1925"
    - Harrison, Jane, undated; 1; Landau, Ergy; 1.0 folder (6 x 8 inches, mounted on card 9.5 x 9.25 inches) (Folder 21)
      One photograph: portrait with Hope Mirrlees inscribed "To Miss Sylvia Beach from Jane Harrison and Hope Mirrlees," stamped on reverse "Studio Landau, Photographie Artistique, 17, Rue Lauriston, Paris, Métro: Étoile"
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1924 February; 1.0 folder
      - Mounted Photograph: Two Portraits Side by Side, One With Hat and Cane, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (each 3.6 x 2.4 inches, together on card 3.5 x 4.75 inches) (Folder 22)
      - Inscribed Photographic Postcard: Standing on a Bridge in Florence, 1924 February; 2; portion of 1 folder (5.25 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 22)
        Inscribed "For Sylvia Beach with highest good wishes—Marsden Hartley, Firenze Feb- 1924"
      - Inscribed Photographic Postcard: On the Steps of Chartres Cathedral, undated; 3; portion of 1 folder (5.25 x 3.25 inches, on card) (Folder 22)
        Inscribed "For Sylvia Beach, This beautiful [?] of Chartres—Marsden Hartley"
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1920-1958 April; portions of 4 boxes
      - Hemingway, Ernest: Inside Shakespeare and Company, circa 1921; 1.0 folder
        - Photograph: Standing in Front of a Bookcase in Shakespeare and Company by Sylvia Beach, 1921; 1; Beach, Sylvia; 2 vintage prints and 2 later prints portion of 1 folder (4.25 x 2.75 inches) (Folder 23)
          Inscribed on reverse "Ernest Hemingway at Shakespeare and Company, by Sylvia Beach, 1921" (includes original negative)
        - Negative: Standing in Front of a Bookcase in Shakespeare and Company by Sylvia Beach, 1921; 1 original negative (Folder 23)
        - Photograph: Sitting in Front of a Bookcase in Shakespeare and Company, undated; 2; 1 print portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 2.75 inches) (Folder 23)
        - Negative: Sitting in Front of a Bookcase in Shakespeare and Company, undated; 1 negative (Folder 23)
      - Hemingway, Ernest: By Man Ray, 1923; portions of 2 boxes
        - Inscribed Formal portrait: Ernest Hemingway by Man Ray, 1923; 1; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 vintage print portion of 1 folder (9.25 x 7 inches (mounted in frame 14.5 x 11.5)) (Folder 1)
          Inscribed "For Sylvia Beach, Ernest Hemingway Aug. 1923," signed "M R, Paris"
        - Copy Print of Inscribed Formal portrait: Ernest Hemingway by Man Ray, undated; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 later copy print (Folder 24)
        - Formal portrait: Ernest Hemingway With Son Jack (Bumby), 1925; 2; Man Ray, 1890-1976; portion of 1 folder (9 x 6.75 inches (mounted in frame 14 x 11)) (Folder 2)
      - Hemingway, Ernest: Attending Bullfights in Spain With Others, 1923-1924; 1 folder
        Dates and locations recorded on prints in this folder appear to conflict, and thus the range of dates 1923-1924 has been applied to all prints even when a date is recorded on the print itself. The locations (Ronda and Pamplona, Spain) also conflict, even when recorded on the print. Researchers are cautioned to confirm both date and locations of images.
        - Snapshot: Bill Bird Standing With Robert McAlmon in Bullring, 1923-1924; 1; 1 vintage print and 3 copy prints (Folder 25)
        - Snapshot: Ernest Hemingway With Robert McAlmon in a Bullring, 1923-1924; 2; 1 vintage print and 2 copy prints portion of 1 folder (2.5 x 1.5 inches) (Folder 25)
        - Snapshot: Ernest Hemingway With Robert McAlmon in a Bullring, 1923-1924; 3; 1 vintage print and 3 copy prints portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 5 inches) (Folder 25)
          inscribed on reverse "Réproduction interdite, copyright by Sylvia Beach" and "Ernest Hemingway, Robert McAlmon in the arena, Pamplona 1924," stamped on reverse "Shakespeare and Company, Library, Sylvia Beach, Paris"
        - Mounted Snapshot: Bill Bird Standing With Robert McAlmon in Bullring, 1923-1924; 4; 1 vintage print portion of 1 folder (1.75 x 2.75 inches, mounted on card 2.75 x 3.25 inches) (Folder 25)
        - Snapshot: McAlmon With Ernest Hemingway Outside Arena in Spain, 1923-1924; 5; 1 vintage print portion of 1 folder (1.75 x 2.75 inches) (Folder 25)
        - Snapshot: Robert McAlmon in Arena, 1923-1924; 6; 1 vintage print (Folder 25)
          Date from hand-written note on back of print.
        - Photographic Postcard: Bull Fight in Arena, 1923-1924; 1; 1 vintage photographic postcard and 4 copy prints (3.5 x 5 inches) (Folder 25)